ICICI Lombard and CNBC tv18 present
India risk management Awards my first
person I didn't meet builders because
you also raise that issue are we a bit
of children or the 2008 crisis that
there we call everything of crisis
I mean maybe more scared of financial
events than live in the past is there if
they're that likelihood I I really don't
think that we always can talk about
crises in the well what would call
systemic which is what we saw in
2008-2009 and then there's always milder
um let me say that uh in terms of how
would I characterize some of the
problems I described for India in in in
banking uh some of those had the element
of boom bust this was around you know
the the 2008 2008 uh and some of them
are what I would call slower burn
they're more structural and this has to
do with the credit allocation in the
publicly owned back so they don't have
that crisis crisis that things are going
to you know and to some important degree
the same distinction is applicable when
we talk about climate change climate
change is I mean it can it can be very
drastic it's the real threat those in in
the real threat in economies that are
facing like Australia large-scale fire
or a tropical storm that's that's
something but many of those risks are
slower burn
but there's still risks um and that's
what I tried to highlight in some of my
presentation the other issue that comes
to the mind is that in spite of this
exponential increase in government debt
and the fact that corporates Amoy
indebted than ever before or certainly
more than they were in the 2008
contraction and thirdly as you pointed
out that interest rates are already
negative and so even the monetary space
is next to nothing in spite of all this
we see global markets equity markets
reaching out to all-time highs and this
is especially the case the United States
which also has much less monetary space
and practically even less fiscal space
yeah are we is this indicating something
different that something right is
happening or is it indicating that this
is a blind spot and we better be worried
about the way equity markets are
charging there are things that are
different there always are we in our
work Ken Rogoff an AI that this time is
different is meant to be ironic but
that's really about human nature which
seldom is different but let me get to
your question on equity markets um part
of the equity market story is definitely
tied to the exceptionally low for long
interest rates there is a search for
yield ah the search for yield is not
just these asset managers that managing
pension funds asset managers that were
once predominantly in fixed income and
have had to seek higher returns in the
equity market it is sovereign wealth
funds that historically like central
banks were predominantly a fixed income
and have to so there are structural
elements to the shift to the extent that
some of the reasons some of the reasons
that interest rates are low have to do
with our aging population some of them
have to do with
our productivity so some of these trends
to lower interest rates are secular
however one has to be prepared that to
the extent that some of the interest
rate decline is not permanent that there
could be adverse shocks inflation
surprises and the like that would lead
even without melodrama to some increase
in interest rates um then I think those
equity markets will be sorely uh tested
because right now I think there's a
great deal of complacency that it's not
that rates are low for long is that
inflation is dead and rates are low
forever which is saying forever in
economics it's always dangerous that's
sort of a rule of thumb okay may I
invite mr. Parker the star to join us
[Applause]
that's because a veteran of managing
risk so I thought I should do is very
you know we've been discussing a lot of
financial issues and how those risks can
be managed and mitigated but uh you know
what you must now be encountering are
you know existential risks but it's
television seriously disrupted by
digital so many people not watching our
programs except apps what's you know
livestock markets the rest of it is
available digitally only sports is
watched because it's a live event so
similar disruptions we have seen for the
automobile sector with Millennials not
wanting to own a car how do you manage
these kinds of risks so leather I don't
think that's something that we insurers
manage that marriage it's I think each
company has to think about how do they
manage their existence and you know you
know ultimately we are all serving
customers customers are human beings who
have needs which transcend time right
there of course these change and morph
in some way or form but the foundation
of those needs are probably similar what
you're talking about is they say in the
case of a car is a transportation need
you want to move from one place to
another in the case of television it's
more may be information or entertainment
the way you provide that solution to
your customer can change and that's what
maybe technology does I think the other
aspect of technology is that you know if
it creates disruption but it also
creates opportunity you know for example
when we look at risk for our own
businesses
we talked about catastrophic risks and
we talked about event dressed etcetera
and let's say in the past traditionally
we would have been waiting for it to
happen and then we come in and you know
let's say you know pay a claim today you
can actually monitor and hence prevent
some of these events using sensors and
and you know for example in the
automobile example that you are talking
about one of the biggest worries that we
have as insurers is that if everyone
moves into autonomous vehicles
self-driven cars the rate of accidents
dropped by 80% what happens to our
business
you're also disrupted right exactly if I
if I can take given the last question
from you either you talked about the
fact that the last question that in your
slide was will us
dollar remain there is a credit card
similar with we were talking there that
this is probably more the most
interesting question to ask so let me
ask you that question since you do not
say right now happy I'm so happy you've
done that um look I just finished a
study with Ken Ken Rogoff who was here
last year and Ethan L seski a former
student of mine uh looking at this very
issue if anything the dollar has gained
ground in the last two years because the
euro uh has lost ground in the euro has
lost ground because yes there is one
year or one currency but there isn't the
unified debt market you have a very
fragmented you have booms you have Greek
debt it's not a it's a fragmented market
um so what worries me is what the
so-called ultra-thin dilemma which to
service as a reserve currency you wish
you more debt because the world wants to
hold more debt but at the same time you
saw the debt numbers for the US so at
one at one point in time the two clash
you know does their does the US yes the
rest of the world wants more debt will
issue more debt and up what at one point
does that mean to a dollar depreciation
at the moment there's no alternative to
the dollar that's no big alternative uh
but that may change over time well it's
an interesting conversation
thank you very much comment I know it
was a pleasure speaking with you
Oscar as well thank you very much for
joining us in this chapter ICICI Lombard
and CNBC tv18 percent India risk
management Awards
[Music]